[Applause]
mr. president upon the recommendation of
the appropriate university committee I
present for the honorary degree of
Doctor of Humane Letters the Honorable
Arnold Schwarzenegger
you Arnold Schwarzenegger are a
self-made man ever a Californian at
heart you are a warrior for the Golden
State a tireless leader in seeking to
protect the environment to advance
scientific discovery and to bring people
together for the common good your
greatest strengths our ambition
discipline and fortitude you're a
devoted public servant in a
philanthropist a gifted entrepreneur and
a statesman here in your adopted country
your name has been immortalized in the
annals of Hollywood and in the archives
of our nation's history for your
inspirational realization of the
American dream your many accomplishments
as a leader actor and sports icon and
your significant contributions in
promoting the state of California the
University of Southern California now
presents you with its highest honor
by the authority vested in me by the
trustees I hereby confer upon you Arnold
Schwarzenegger the degree of Doctor of
Humane Letters honoris causa please
accept our warmest congratulations
[Applause]
and now it's my great pleasure to ask
dr. Schwarzenegger to offer the 2009
commencement address for the University
of Southern California thank you well
thank you very much
hello everybody what a great
introduction what a wonderful thing what
a great great welcome I'm getting here
so thank you very much I mean I haven't
heard applause like that since I
announced that I was going to stop
acting but anyway it is really terrific
to see here so many graduate students
and undergraduate students and
graduating here today I heard that
they're 4,500 graduating here today and
undergraduate students so this is
fantastic there's 2200 men 2300 women
and five five four listed yourselves as
undecided so this is a really a great
great bunch of people here I love it
but seriously president sample trustees
faculty family friends and graduates it
is a tremendous privilege to stand
before you this morning there's nothing
that I enjoy more than celebrating great
achievements and it don't just mean your
parents celebrating never having to pay
another tuition bill that's another that
I'm talking about I'm talking about just
celebrating the great accomplishment so
let's let me congratulate the Trojans
class the Trojan goes of 2009 on your
graduation from one of the finest
universities in the world let's give our
graduates a tremendous round of applause
what a special day what a great
accomplishment
now this is an equally special day of
course for the parents for the
grandparents siblings and other family
members who support made all of this the
day possible and let's not forget of
course the professors those dedicated
individuals who taught you who came up
with exciting ways to share your vast
wisdom knowledge and experience with you
and I must also say thank you to
president sample for honoring me with
this fantastic degree
thank you very much Wow Arnold
Schwarzenegger Doctor of Humane Letters
I love it but of course I noticed that
it wasn't a doctorate in film or in
cinema or in acting I wonder why but
anyway that's okay I think whatever I
can get but maybe now since I'm the
doctor I can go back up to Sacramento
maybe now the Legislature will finally
listen to me but anyway I stand before
you today not just as dr. Schwarzenegger
or as Governor Schwarzenegger or as the
Terminator was Conan the Barbarian
but also as a proud new member of this
Trojan family now some of you may know
that my daughter just completed her
freshman year right here and one of the
most exciting things for me has been to
learn about the great traditions that
make this University so wonderful and so
special but hora dogged me all about for
instance the victreebel she set me down
and she told me about it weighs on 295
pounds and how the winner of the annual
football game between USC and UCLA takes
the spell and gets the painted in the
school colors and I stopped in the
middle of talking I said wait a minute
captain back up a little bit I UCLA has
a football team
of course my daughter's journey here at
USC is just beginning and us is ending
and I know that you're a little bit
stressed out right now as you start this
exciting new chapter in your lives some
people say it is scary to leave the
comfort of the university and to go out
into the cold hard world but I have to
tell you something I think this is a
bunch of nonsense because after all this
is America this is the greatest country
on Earth with the greatest opportunities
I mean it is one thing if you were born
in Afghanistan or in smart Valley
it's what Valley and back is done where
you be forced to join the Taliban or be
killed now then they will say yes that
is a little bit scary but this this is
going to be a piece of cake for you
trust me you live in America and you're
prepared for the future with this
tremendous education you've got me of
one of the greatest universities in the
world this is going to be exciting it's
a great adventure and this is a new face
in your life this is going to be awesome
now of course this journey is not going
to be without any setbacks and failures
or disappointments that's just the way
life is but you're ready and you're able
and you would not be here today with
your degrees and with your honors if you
wouldn't be ready so now of course to
help you along the way I thought that
the best gift that could give you today
is it will give you a few of my own
personal ideas and how to be successful
and parents I just want you to know
maybe you should close your ears you
should plug your ears because maybe the
few things that you maybe don't like
what I have to say but there any way I
can explain how I became successful in
who I am today
by going through what I call dr.
Schwarzenegger six rules of success
of course people ask me all the time
they say to me what is the secret to
success and I give them always the short
version I say number one come to America
number two work your butt off and number
three marry a Kennedy but anyway but
anyway this is the short rules now the
day I'm going to give you the six rules
of success but before I start that is
one of the stages are my rules and I
think that they can apply to anyone but
that is for you to decide because not
everyone is the same there's some people
that just like to kick back and coast
through life and I just want to be very
intense and want to be number one and
want to be successful let's like me I
always wanted to be very intense I
always wanted to be number one I took it
very seriously in my career so this was
the same when I started with
bodybuilding I didn't want to just be a
bodybuilding champion I wanted to be the
best body build of all times the same
was in the movies I didn't want to just
be a movie star I wanted to be a great
movie star that's the highest paid movie
star and have the buff the title
building and so this intensity always
paid off for me this commitment always
paid off for me
so here are some of the rules the first
rule is trust yourself
and what I mean but that is so many
young people are getting so much advice
from their parents and from the teachers
from everyone but what is most important
is that you have to dig deep down dig
deep down and ask yourselves who do you
want to be not what but who and I'm
talking about not with your parents and
teachers want you to be with you I'm
talking about figuring out for
yourselves what makes you happy no
matter how crazy it may sound to the
people I was lucky growing up because I
did not have the television or I didn't
have telephones I didn't have the TV the
computers in the iPods and of course
Twitter was then something that birds
did outside the window I didn't have all
those destructions in orders have spent
a lot of time for myself so could figure
out and listen to what is inside my
heart and inside my head and I
recognized very quickly that inside my
head and heart
a burning desire to leave my small
village in Austria not that there was
something wrong with us Austria it's a
beautiful country but I wanted to leave
that little place and want to be part of
something big the United States of
America a powerful nation the place
where dreams can come true I knew when I
come over here I can realize my dreams
and I decided that the best way for me
to come to America was to become a
bodybuilding champion because they knew
that was my ticket the instant that I
saw magazine cover of my idol reg Park
he was mr. universe he was starring in
Hercules movies he looked strong and
powerful he was so confident so when I
found out he got that way I became
obsessed and I went home and I said to
my family I want to be a bodybuilding
champion now you can imagine how that
went over in my home in Austria my
parents they couldn't believe it it
would have been just happy if I would
have become a police officer like my
father or married someone like Heidi who
had a bunch of them had a bunch of kids
and ran around like the fun trap family
in Sound of Music that's what my family
had in mind for me but something else
burned inside me something burned inside
me I wanted to be different I was
determined to be unique I was driven to
think big in the dream big everyone else
thought that I was crazy my friend said
if you want to be a champion in a sport
why don't you go and become a bicycle
champion or a skiing champion or soccer
champion those are the Austrian sports
but I didn't care I wanted to be a
bodybuilding champion and used that to
come to America and use that to go into
the movies and make millions of dollars
so of course for extra motivation I read
books on strongmen and a bodybuilding
and looked at magazines and one of the
things that it was I decorated my
bedroom window of a bedroom wall right
next to my bed it was this big wall that
had decorated all with pictures hung up
pictures of strongmen and bodybuilders
and wrestlers in boxes and so on and it
was so excited about this great
decoration that it took my mother to the
bedroom and I showed her and she shook
her head she was absolutely in shock and
tears started running down her eyes and
she called the doctor she called a house
doctor
and she brought him in and she explained
to him there's something wrong here she
said she looked at the wall with the
darkness this is where did I go wrong I
mean all of Arnold's friends have
pictures in the wall of girls and Arnold
has all this man but it's not just men
they're half naked and they are oiled up
with baby oil and what is going on here
where did I go wrong so you can imagine
the doctor shook his head and he said
there's nothing wrong at this age you
have idols and you go and half does this
is just quite normal so this is rule
number one I wanted to become a champion
I wanted I was on a mission so rule
number one is of course trust yourself
no matter how and what anyone else
thinks
and of course who number two is break
the rules we have so many rules in life
about everything I said break the rules
not the law but break the rules my wife
has a t-shirt my wife has a t-shirt that
says well-behaved women rarely and make
history well you know I don't want to
burst her bubble but the same is true
with man it is impossible to be a
maverick or true original if you're too
well behaved and don't want to break the
rules you have to think outside the box
that's what I believe after all what is
the point of being on this earth if all
you want to do is be like to everyone
and avoid trouble the only way that ever
got any place was the breaking some of
the rules after all I remember that
after I was finished with my
bodybuilding career I wanted to get into
acting and want to be a star in films
you can imagine what the agent said when
I went to meet all those agents everyone
had the same line that it can't be done
the rules are different here just look
at your body here if this huge monstrous
body and overly developed that doesn't
fit into the movies you don't understand
this was 20 years ago the Hercules
movies now there is the little guys that
ain't Dustin Hoffman Woody Allen
Chuck Nicholson before he gained weight
of course that is but anyway those are
the guys that win and the agent also
complained about Max and he says no one
ever became a star with an accent like
that especially not with the joy
an accent in yes I can imagine with your
name Arnold Schwarzenegger all or
whatever the name is on a billboard yeah
that's going to draw a lot of tickets
and sell a lot of tickets you're right
so this is the kind of negative attitude
they had but I didn't listen to those
rules even though they were very nice
and they said look we can get you some
big parts be kingmaker get you to be a
you know being a wrestler or a bouncer
oh maybe with the German accent we can
get it to be a Nazi officer in Hogan's
Heroes or something like that but you
know I didn't listen to orders this were
their rules not my rules I was convinced
I could do it that if I worked as hard
as I didn't bodybuilding five hours a
day and I started getting to work I
started taking acting classes took
English classes took speech classes
dialogue classes accent removal classes
I even took I remember running around a
fine wine grows and a vine see because
Germans had difficulties with the F and
the W and the V so fine wine grows on
the vine
I know what some of you now say is I
hope that Arnold got his money back but
let me tell you something I had a good
time doing those things and it really
helped me finally I broke through I
broke through and I started getting the
first part in TV streets of San
Francisco Lucille Ball hired me and made
pumping iron stay hungry and then I got
the big break in Conan the Barbarian and
there the director said if we wouldn't
have Schwarzenegger we would have to
build one now think about that
and then when ADA Terminator I'll be
back became most of one of the most
famous lines in a movie history
all because of my crazy accent now think
about it the things that the agent said
will be totally a detriment and will be
impossible for me to get a job all of a
sudden became an asset for me all of the
things my accent my body and everything
so it just shows you never listen that
you can't do something and you have to
work your way up of course run for
something else first I mean it was the
same when I ran for governor the same
lines that if the rug give up it can't
be done and then of course I ran for
governor
and the rest of course is history they
said you have to start with a small job
as mayor and then there's a simply man
and then he was lieutenant governor and
then as governor and he said that's the
way it works in a political career I
said I'm not interested in the political
career I want to be a public servant I
want to fix California's problems and
bring people together and bring the
parties together so like I said I
decided to run I didn't pay attention to
the rules and I made it and the rest is
history which of course brings me to
rule number three don't be afraid to
fail anything I've ever attempted I was
always willing to fail in the movie
business I remember that you pick
scripts many times you think this is a
winning script but then of course you
find out later on when you do the movie
that it didn't work and the movie goes
in the toilet now we have seen my movies
I'm in red Sonia Hercules in New York
last action heroes those movies went in
the toilet but that's okay because
they're the same time they made movies
like Terminator and Conan and True Lies
and predator and twins that went through
the roof so you can't always win but
don't be afraid of making decisions you
can't be paralyzed by fear or failure or
you would never push yourself you keep
pushing because you believe in yourself
and in your vision and you know that
it's the right thing to do and success
will come so don't be afraid to fail
which brings me the rule number four
which is don't listen to the naysayers I
mean how many times have you hear that
you can't do this and you can't do that
and it has never been done before just
imagine if Bill Gates had quit when
people say it can't be done I hear this
all the time some effect I love it when
someone says that never no one has ever
done this before because they mean I do
it that means that I'm the first one
that has done it so pay no attention to
the people who say you can't be done I
remember my mother-in-law eunice Kennedy
Shriver when she started Special
Olympics in 1968 people say that it
would not work the experts the doctors
that specialized in mental disabilities
in mental retardation said it can't be
done you can't bring people out of the
institution you can't make them
participate in sports in jumpy
in swimming and in running that will
hurt themselves to reward each other
they would drown in the pool what let me
tell you something now 40 years later
Special Olympics is one of the greatest
organizations in 164 countries dedicated
to people with mental disabilities and
with intellectual challenge and
intellectual challenge and she did not
take nope one answer and the same is
when you look at Barack Obama I mean
imagine if he would have listened if he
would have listened to the naysayers he
would have never run for president
people say that couldn't be done that he
couldn't get elected that he couldn't
beat Hillary Clinton that he would never
win the general election but he followed
his own heart he didn't listen to the
you can't and he changed the course of
American history
so Oh when over you see that if I would
have listened to the naysayers I would
still be in the Austrian Alps yodeling I
would never have come to America I would
have never met my wonderful wife Maria
Shriver I would have never had the
wonderful four kids that would have
never done terminated and I wouldn't be
standing here in front of you that they
as governor of the greatest state of the
greatest country in the world so I never
listened that you can't I always
listened to myself and said yes you can
that brings me to rule number five which
is the most important rule of world of
all work your butt off you never want
the film because he didn't work hard
enough I never wanted to lose a
competition or lose an election because
they didn't work hard enough I always
believed leaving no stone unturned
Muhammad Ali one of my great heroes had
a great line in the 70s when he was
asked how many sit-ups do you do he said
I don't count my sit-ups I only start
counting when it starts hurting when
they feel pain that's when I start
counting because that's when it really
counts that's what makes you a champion
that's the way it isn't everything no
pain no gain
so many of those lessons that I apply in
life I have learned from sports let me
tell you and especially that one and let
me tell you it is important to have fun
in life of course but when you're out
there partying horsing around someone
out there at the same time is working
hard someone is getting smarter and
someone is winning just remember that
now if you want to coast through life
don't pay any attention to any of those
rules but if you want to win there's
absolutely no way around hard hard work
none of my rules by the way of success
will work unless you do I've always
figured out that there's 24 hours a day
you sleep six hours and if 18 hours left
I know there's some of you out there now
and says well wait a minute I sleep
eight hours or nine hours well then just
sleep faster I would recommend because
you only need to sleep six hours then if
eighteen hours left there's a lot of
things you can accomplish as a matter of
fact dead Turner used to say always
early to bed early to rise Brooke like
hell and advertise and of course all you
know this is you know already those
things because otherwise you wouldn't be
sitting here today just remember you
can't climb the ladder of success with
your hands in the pocket that takes me
to rule number six which is a very
important or it's about giving back
whatever path did you take in your lives
you must always find time to give
something back something back to your
community give something back to your
state or to your country and my
father-in-law Sargent Shriver who is a
great American truly great American who
started the Peace Corps the Job Corps
legal aid to the poor he said that Yale
University to the students at the
commencement speech tear down that mural
tear down that mirror that makes you
always look at yourself and you will be
able to look beyond that mural and you
will see the millions of people didn't
need your help
let me tell you something reaching out
and helping people will bring you more
satisfaction than anything else you have
ever done as a matter of fact the day
after having worked for Special Olympics
never started after-school programs have
promoted fitness and now with my job as
governor I can tell you playing a game
of chess with an eight-yard kid in the
inner-city school is far more exciting
for me than walking down another red
carpet of a movie premiere so let me
tell you as you prepare to go off into
the world remember the six rules trust
yourself
break some rules don't be afraid to fail
ignore the naysayers Brooke like hell
and give something back and now let me
leave you with one final thought and I
will be brief I promise this University
was conceived in 1880 back when Los
Angeles was just a small frontier town
125 classes of Trojans have gone before
you
they have Satya exactly where you sit
today in times good times and in bad in
times of war and in times of peace in
times of great promise and in times of
great uncertainty through it all this
great country this great state this
great University have stood tall and
persevered we are tough times now and
there's a lot of uncertainty in the
world but there's one thing certain
we'll be back and we will be back we
will be back stronger and more
prosperous than ever before because that
is what California and America has
always done the ancient Trojans were
known for their fighting spirit their
refusal to give up the ability to
overcome great odds
so as you graduate today never lose that
optimism and that fighting spirit never
lose the spirit of Troy because remember
this is America
and you are USC Trojans proud strong and
ready to soar
congratulations and God bless of you
thank you very much thank you
[Applause]